Let's talk about an interesting command line interface, that was a Windows Management
Instrumentation command line, we call it as WMIC, so this is one of the wonderful features
in Windows, so you can launch any kind of process from this command line, okay.
So you can just say WMIC process called create, so now we can see the calculator has been
opened in the backend, right.
So with the process area of 13, 4, 8 and written value 0, so the command line was executed
and it triggered a process CLC, okay.
So this is one of the utility, the threat technology using to launch multiple process, okay.
So in case, if you need to install a ransomware in the remote environment, you can use
WMIC to do that, so in our scenario we are going to do that and we are installing a ransomware.
So if you want to launch any kind of process, even you can launch a notepad or anything,
okay, so you can launch a notepad.exe orepad.exe, okay.
So this will be like this, you can launch any kind of process, okay.
So think about one thing, let's me show you from here, let me take an impact from this
we know we will be getting higher over a privilege, like system privilege from the impact
and system mandatory level, if I launch any kind of process from here, let me close the
calculator, you can close the command line and we can launch the count now, so you can
see the process ID, there was created 13, 4, 4 and written value, written the value
0, right.
So if you go to the target machine, Windows machine, in the result it was saying it,
in the result it was saying, it's like the process has been launched and process has been
successful launched, right, with the process ID, but if I go to the target machine, there
is no process, you will not find any process in the backend, so what was the reason, okay.
But if I launch anything, if I launch anything from here, so now it was opening a calculator
in the, in the GUI graph, it leaves interface, but in, if I open, if I execute this command,
if I open the calculator from the system privilege at the network level, because we are,
we are using a impact connection and we are in a network level, right.
So we did not, we do not see any kind of, any kind of calculator has been open.
So now my, now the machine was like blank, let, let's call, let's use WMI-C2 create process.
So now again, it was saying the process has been launched and, but you can't find it in the,
in the target machine.
So the reason is, WMI-C worked with two sections, section 0 and section 1, okay.
So basically, section 0 is like, so this is like, this section 0 is like a non-interactive
section, okay.
So the section 0 is like a non-interactive section, we are, we didn't interacted with the
target machine, right, we didn't interact with the target machine, we just executed everything
from the remote call emission, right, from the attacker call emission, okay.
So we will be calling this as a non-interactive, as a section 0.
So if any process with a section, launched with the section 0, okay, maybe the higher
privilege, anti-system, from this system privilege, okay.
If any process launched with the system privilege, the system and the trigger privilege,
it will not show, it will not show in the graphical user interface, okay.
It will not open the particular task, but it will run that task or service in the back,
okay.
So if you need to run any kind of task in the background, without knowing the user, you
can use the WMIC in packet or remote session and you can launch that, okay.
So to find, it was working properly, I was executing this command, okay, let me do this one.
And let me launch this command.
So now it was saying the process was created and it ran the value, it was executed successfully,
let's find out the target machine.
So we just executed a WMI to CMD.exe and we saved the output into the WMI.txt in a
term folder.
Let's move on to that directory and we'll check whether we have the format TXT or not.
Okay, here you can find the format was there and into the authority system, right.
It was successfully launched and it was successfully executed, okay.
So this is called a session zero.
So everything runs in the background, okay, so we will not find, okay, we will not find
an interactive section, we will not find that GUI, you will not find the interface, whatever,
okay.
If I launch the calculator from session zero, you will not find in the target interface,
But the session one is like interactive user, okay, it's an interactive thing, okay.
So if you launch anything from the interactive session zero, like running as an administrator
mode, okay.
So only we'll be getting a system, only let's, let me tell you, okay, my slash all.
So here you can find it's a high mandatory level, it's in the administrator privilege, right.
So if I launch anything here, so now the calculator has been open, right.
But if I launch anything from the system level, system mandatory level of privilege, but
it was not opening anything, okay.
So that's the difference between the session zero and session zero, okay.
So that type of utilizing this and they are like executing the ransomware inside the environment.
Okay.
So this is nothing simple, if we, yeah, so it's a, it's a simple command.
So you need to give the IP address of the machine, so 18.our IP address 94 and you need
to be the domain and the user is a user and how domain is like win, df, a well, two to one
on something, and password is password.
So if we execute this command from any remote machine, so it will directly calling the
ransomware.exe, right, so you can execute anything.
If you, if your file is in your server, you can use this command, PowerShell and you can download
the strings and you can execute this.
So this is how the threat tactics will be delivering the malware and installing the malware
through WMIC.
So WMIC is one of a better thing to execute the ransomware, except not only WMIC, we have
seen plenty of other things, execution parts, like, you can execute through CMD.exe,
PowerShell.exe, and we have, we have a lot of methods, right, even you can take a command
control to any disk and you can, W can't the application.
So that's also one of the thing, so there is multiple ways to execute, but this is,
this is one of the way I need to, I need to let you know everyone, because if you are doing
a threat investigations, if you are doing some kind of foreign, you need to understand,
this is also one of a scenario that the threat tactics will be, will launch the WMIC to execute
any kind of files, okay.
So that's all about this video, will, will execute the ransomware in the next video, okay.
So the thing is, I don't want to, I don't want to corrupt my primary machine, okay, corrupt
my Windows, this working machine, because I need to give the Windows machine to you,
in the lab section.
So because of that, I just attached my previous, one of the video, which I have recorded
previously, executing a ransomware, and you can see that in the next video, so how, how
the system will act, for one scene is telling a ransomware, okay.
So I'll be giving this machine, which I am working, I'll be giving this Windows machine
pinned out two to one one, which we have used as a target in the lab section, right.
So you have installed, maybe you have, you have already installed.
So this is the scenario, and let's hop off from here, and we'll continue our discussion
in the next video, see you guys, bye bye.